# MUHAMMAD RISQI FIRDAUS

# **Software Engineer**

Bandung, Indonesia | +6282245200501 | Email: risqi.firdaus20@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mrfirdauss/ | github.com/mrfirdauss-20 | mrfirdauss.vercel.app

### **SUMMARY**

An undergraduate informatic student who has a devotion and experience in digitalization, especially in web and database. Keen to learn about building and developing technological things. Specialized in web development and data using various stacks (PHP, Node js, Golang, Python). He is able to quickly learn and acclimate to new technologies. Besides that, he has a lot of experience being a leader in teams and organizations.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

### PT Paragon Technology and Innovation – Jakarta, Indonesia

Backend Engineer Intern (April 2022- Present)

- Building an endpoint for a warehouse management system using PostgreSQL and express js.
- Responsible for optimizing the gueries and databases.
- Filling web testing documentation.

### Hikeryco – Bandung, Indonesia

Chief Technology Officer (July 2021 - Now)

- Developing websites using PHP and MySQL for web services.
- Deploying the web via IDCloudhost VM platform and maintaining DNS for www.hikery.co.

### GhazLabs Indonesia – Bandung, Indonesia

Software Engineer Intern (April 2022- May 2022)

- Developed web app using Golang and various memory such as Redis, MySQL, and elasticsearch.
- Experienced in building Golang architecture using hex architecture and implemented docker-compose.

### Skillup – Bandung, Indonesia

Vice Manager of Technology (September 2021 - April 2022)

 Responsible for developing and coordinating a team consisting of 4 people on web development and also with other departments.

# **Schoolpad.id** – Bandung, Indonesia

Quality Assurance (September 2020 - December 2020)

- Checked and tested the quality of try-out questions that will be served to more than 10.000 users.
- Check any bugs on the website, and try out the system, and user experience.

# **EDUCATION**

# **INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI BANDUNG (2020 - Present)**

B.Eng, Informatic Engineering - GPA 3.16/4.0 for 74 credits

# **PROJECTS**

# **Personal Website**

Web Developer (May 2021)

Built a personal landing page using React. The timeline component was developed using Material UI. Deployed the website on <u>vercel</u>.

## **Workoutin Web Apps**

Web Developer (May 2021)

eCommerce web app that gives user solutions for looking for a personal trainer. Built a web app using React, Next and Firebase. Responsible for building a personal trainer details page and chat services. Also responsible for deploying web on AWS Amplify. The chat service was built using a realtime database, firebase. The clone on <u>vercel</u>.

### **DNA and Disease WebApp**

Backend Developer (May 2021)

DNA and Disease WebApp is a web that is able to compare the DNA of patients and disease DNA using Boyer Moore and KMP Algorithm, filter the input, determine the distance of the DNA and save the data of DNA and search history in MySQL. This web application was built using MySQL, expressjs and React. Responsible for developing the server application and building the Levenshtein distance algorithm.

# **Website Image Compressor**

Backend Developer (May 2021)

The web application is built using Python Flask. This application is able to compress an input image using the SVD image matrix algorithm. Responsible for developing the web server request and sending services.

# **Workout.in Desktop Application**

Software Developer (April 2021)

Developing a dynamic desktop app using pyqt. Building end to end applications from DB to interface. Filling testing and requirement documentation. Responsible for developing dashboard and input workout services.

#### Konsul.in

Backend Developer (January 2021)

Konsulin is a consultation web that was built for muslimhackfest 2021. Was responsible for leading the development team. Develop Whatsapp chatbot and website services using node js. Maintaining the JQuery for the websites. Deploying the web via Heroku (bit.ly/Konsulln).

### **ADDITIONAL**

**Technical skills:** Python (Matplotlib, Pandas, Seaborn, Sklearn), MySQL, NodeJs, PHP, Problem Solving, Web Development, Excel (<u>Linkedin Certification</u>), Redis, Golang, Elasticsearch, Docker, CSS (<u>Linkedin Certification</u>), Sequelize, React, firebase.

Language: English, Arabic

**Awards:** Best Mentee (Top 1%) among 1000 mentees Digistar Telkom 2022, Top 6th Paragon Hackathon Competition, Semifinalist of Muslim HackFest 2021, Semifinalist HackGov UGM 2021, Awardee Beasiswa Pembinaan Rumah Kepemimpinan